RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
القيامة القيامة.
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
رفض القصص والحروف. هنا كانت ملهمة من قبل تاريخنا.
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
لا توجد حيوانات ضارة خلال. الفيلم من هذا الإنتاج.
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
1225 - KAYI TRIBE
-Great God!
-Only one God!
الإله العظيم. إله واحد فقط.
-Great God!
-Only one God!
الإله العظيم. إله واحد فقط.
-Great God!
-Only one God!
الإله العظيم. إله واحد فقط.
-Great God!
-Only one God!
الإله العظيم. إله واحد فقط.
-Great God!
-Only one God!
Even the iron could not stand
reciting of God and gave in.
حتى الحديد لا يمكن أن يقف. قراءة الله واستسلم.
Even the iron could not stand
reciting of God and gave in.
Wait a bit!
انتظر قليلا.
Take a look at this one.
الق نظرة على هذا.
This is magnificent. I pity the enemy whom
this will be the Azrael of.
هذا رائع أنا أشفق على العدو منه. هذا سيكون عزرائيل.
This is magnificent. I pity the enemy whom
this will be the Azrael of.
In the hands of a valiant like you...
في يد الباسلة مثلك.
...let it be the sound of the oppressed,
wrath to the tyrants, if God permits.
فليكن صوت المظلومين. غضب على الطغاة ، إذا سمح الله.
...let it be the sound of the oppressed,
wrath to the tyrants, if God permits.
There’s no sword other than Zulfiqar and
no valiant other than His Holiness Ali.
ليس هناك سيف سوى ذو الفقار و. لا الشجاعة سوى قداسة علي.
There’s no sword other than Zulfiqar and
no valiant other than His Holiness Ali.
I’m ready to sacrifice myself for God,
who gave you to us.
أنا مستعد للتضحية بنفسي من أجل الله. الذي أعطاك لنا.
I’m ready to sacrifice myself for God,
who gave you to us.
For the love of God, in the name of my
forefather Oguz, I’ll gird it with honor.
لمحبة الله ، باسم بلدي. أوجوز الجد ، أنا سوف يربطها بشرف.
For the love of God, in the name of my
forefather Oguz, I’ll gird it with honor.
Bring your hands.
أحضر يديك
What is the matter?
Your tumblers are restless again.
ما المشكلة؟. البهلوانات الخاص بك لا يهدأ مرة أخرى.
What is the matter?
Your tumblers are restless again.
We are going hunting.
نحن ذاهبون للصيد.
They are getting ready.
انهم يستعدون.
Are there any animals left to hunt
in this famine?
هل هناك أي حيوانات تركت للصيد. في هذه المجاعة؟
Are there any animals left to hunt
in this famine?
You are right but...
أنت على حق ولكن.
...hunting keeps the Alps fit.
الصيد يحافظ على تناسب جبال الألب.
It is better if we find a way to keep
the tribe alive as well.
من الأفضل أن نجد طريقة للحفاظ عليها. القبيلة على قيد الحياة كذلك.
It is better if we find a way to keep
the tribe alive as well.
That can only be decided
on the headquarters tomorrow.
لا يمكن إلا أن تقرر. في المقر غدا.
That can only be decided
on the headquarters tomorrow.
If we don’t migrate from this highland
before winter, we would be doomed.
إذا كنا لا تهاجر من هذا المرتفع. قبل الشتاء ، سيكون مصيرنا.
If we don’t migrate from this highland
before winter, we would be doomed.
But if you say that you know a solution,
tell us as well.
ولكن إذا قلت إنك تعرف الحل ، أخبرنا كذلك.
But if you say that you know a solution,
tell us as well.
My brother Gundogdu knows
these matters better than me.
أخي Gundogdu يعلم. هذه الأمور أفضل مني.
My brother Gundogdu knows
these matters better than me.
If you wish, talk to him.
إذا كنت ترغب في التحدث معه.
With Gundogdu?
مع جوندوجو؟
No, he never breaths a single word about.
لا ، إنه لا يتنفس أبدا.
Is this what you bought for 40 coins?
هل هذا ما اشتريته مقابل 40 قطعة نقدية؟
This is called a map.
وهذا ما يسمى خريطة.
What is it used for?
ما هو استخدامها ل؟
Look, we are here.
انظر ، نحن هنا.
Right at where these mountains are.
الحق في مكان هذه الجبال.
This is Aleppo. This is Baghdad.
هذا حلب هذا بغداد.
And this is Damascus.
وهذه هي دمشق.
And this is Konya,
where the Sultan’s palace is.
وهذا هو قونية ،. حيث قصر السلطان.
And this is Konya,
where the Sultan’s palace is.
Let go of the palaces
of the sultans and khans and...
تخلص من القصور. من السلاطين والخانات و.
Let go of the palaces
of the sultans and khans and...
...tell us where the tribe should
migrate to, Gundogdu.
قل لنا أين يجب أن القبيلة. الهجرة إلى ، جوندوجو.
...tell us where the tribe should
migrate to, Gundogdu.
The elders are having a dumb moment.
Your father is quiet.
الشيوخ يواجهون لحظة غبية. والدك هادئ.
The elders are having a dumb moment.
Your father is quiet.
He just sits in his tent like
a worrier not a warrior.
يجلس فقط في خيمته مثل. قلق ليس المحارب.
He just sits in his tent like
a worrier not a warrior.
Where is this place?
اين يوجد ذلك المكان؟.
Everyone will learn tomorrow
at headquarters.
الجميع سيتعلم غدا. في المقر.
Everyone will learn tomorrow
at headquarters.
You found a place, right?
وجدت مكان ، أليس كذلك؟
Please tell me, where is it?
من فضلك قل لي ، أين هو؟
Ertugrul!
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟.
I am going hunting, brother.
انا ذاهب للصيد أخي.
This is not the time to go hunting.
We have headquarters tomorrow.
ليس هذا هو الوقت المناسب للذهاب للصيد. لدينا مقر غدا.
This is not the time to go hunting.
We have headquarters tomorrow.
The headquarter is yours
and hunt is mine, brother.
المقر الرئيسي لك. وصيد لي يا أخي.
The headquarter is yours
and hunt is mine, brother.
Alright. But don’t go too far.
Go quickly, come back quickly.
حسنا ولكن لا تذهب بعيدا. الذهاب بسرعة ، والعودة بسرعة.
Alright. But don’t go too far.
Go quickly, come back quickly.
What are you doing with that meat?
We are going hunting, did you forget?
ماذا تفعل مع هذا اللحم؟ نحن نذهب للصيد ، هل نسيت؟
What are you doing with that meat?
We are going hunting, did you forget?
We won’t let you starve during a hunt,
don’t you worry.
لن نسمح لك بالتضور جوعًا أثناء عملية مطاردة. لا تقلق
We won’t let you starve during a hunt,
don’t you worry.
How can you call a valiant as valiant if
he starves while he is hunting, Turgut?
كيف يمكنك استدعاء الباسلة كما الباسلة إذا. يتضور جوعاً وهو يصطاد يا تورجوت؟
How can you call a valiant as valiant if
he starves while he is hunting, Turgut?
-This is just for the road.
-It is impossible to relieve your hunger.
هذا هو فقط للطريق. من المستحيل تخفيف جوعك.
-This is just for the road.
-It is impossible to relieve your hunger.
Come on, Alps.
هيا ، جبال الألب.
Your man is going.
رجلك ذاهب.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
TEMPLARS CASTLE
أمانوس ماونتنز. قلعة النماذج.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
TEMPLARS CASTLE
Guard duty is your pride!
واجب الحرس هو فخرك.
Guard duty is your honor!
واجب الحرس هو شرفك.
If you betray your pride and honor...
إذا كنت تخون كبرياءك وشرفك.
...your death will not come
from the enemy, but from me!
موتك لن يأتي. من العدو ، ولكن مني.
...your death will not come
from the enemy, but from me!
You have honored us, Ustad-i Azam.
لقد كرمتنا يا استادي عزام.
That honor belongs to us.
هذا الشرف ملك لنا.
-Elanora.
-Commander Titus.
Elanora. القائد تيتوس.
-Elanora.
-Commander Titus.
I hope your journey was fine.
آمل أن تكون رحلتك بخير.
Is everything alright, Titus?
هل كل شيء على ما يرام يا تيتوس؟
We are safer than ever, sir.
نحن أكثر أمانا من أي وقت مضى ، يا سيدي.
Your chambers are ready, sir.
Would you like to rest before lunch?
غرفتك جاهزة يا سيدي. هل ترغب في الراحة قبل الغداء؟
Your chambers are ready, sir.
Would you like to rest before lunch?
Elanora may rest. We have work to do.
Elanora قد راحة لدينا عمل للقيام به.
-As you wish.
-With your permission.
كما تتمنا. بعد إذنك.
-As you wish.
-With your permission.
What is the latest development
about the prisoners?
ما هو آخر التطورات. عن الأسرى؟
What is the latest development
about the prisoners?
I gave that duty to my brother Bisol.
أنا أعطيت هذا الواجب لأخي بيسول.
They will submit Numan and his family
to Karatoygar.
سوف يقدمون نعمان وعائلته. لكاراتويغار.
They will submit Numan and his family
to Karatoygar.
For the others, I waited for you.
بالنسبة للآخرين ، انتظرت لك.
Good.
جيد.
Where are they taking us, father?
أين يأخذوننا يا أبي؟
To our palace, son.
إلى قصرنا يا بني.
We will be free there, right?
سنكون أحرار هناك ، أليس كذلك؟
Until eternity, son.
حتى الخلود يا بني.
Until eternity.
حتى الخلود.
So out fate was to return to Konya
like this.
لذلك كان مصير العودة إلى قونية. مثله.
So out fate was to return to Konya
like this.
To the palace we were born in and
grew up, to be killed by our uncle.
إلى القصر ولدنا في و. نشأ ، لقتل من قبل عمنا.
To the palace we were born in and
grew up, to be killed by our uncle.
I will not let anything to happen
to you or your brother, my daughter.
لن اسمح لأي شيء أن يحدث. لك أو لأخيك يا ابنتي.
I will not let anything to happen
to you or your brother, my daughter.
This way Karatoygar will be
dependent on us more than ever.
بهذه الطريقة سوف Karatoygar يكون. تعتمد علينا أكثر من أي وقت مضى.
This way Karatoygar will be
dependent on us more than ever.
It is very important for him to win
the favor of Sultan Aladdin.
من المهم جدا بالنسبة له أن يفوز. صالح السلطان علاء الدين.
It is very important for him to win
the favor of Sultan Aladdin.
Karatoygar becoming a high officer
in the Seljuk court will relieve us.
Karatoygar تصبح ضابطا عاليا. في محكمة السلجوق يريحنا.
Karatoygar becoming a high officer
in the Seljuk court will relieve us.
KARATOYGAR INN
-We did everything as you ordered, sir.
-Okay!
لقد فعلنا كل شيء كما طلبت يا سيدي. حسنا.
-We did everything as you ordered, sir.
-Okay!
Head of guard!
رئيس الحرس.
Are the Turkmen tribes paying
their taxes?
هل تدفع القبائل التركمانية؟ ضرائبهم؟
Are the Turkmen tribes paying
their taxes?
We can’t control them, sir.
They are always on the move.
لا يمكننا السيطرة عليها يا سيدي. هم دائما على هذه الخطوة.
We can’t control them, sir.
They are always on the move.
-Which one is the biggest tribe?
-Kayi tribe, sir.
أيهم أكبر قبيلة؟ قبيلة كايي يا سيدي.
-Which one is the biggest tribe?
-Kayi tribe, sir.
They ran away from the Mongol invasion.
هربوا من الغزو المغولي.
-Who is their leader?
-Suleyman Shah.
من هو قائدهم؟ سليمان شاه.
-Who is their leader?
-Suleyman Shah.
-How many tents?
-2000 tents. But they are well respected.
كم خيام؟ 2000 خيمة لكنها محترمة
-How many tents?
-2000 tents. But they are well respected.
-Do they pay their taxes?
-They do, sir.
هل يدفعون ضرائبهم؟ يفعلون يا سيدي.
-Do they pay their taxes?
-They do, sir.
Good.
جيد.
Then, they shall pay their taxes
earlier this year.
ثم يدفعون ضرائبهم. في وقت سابق من هذا العام.
Then, they shall pay their taxes
earlier this year.
-But, sir...
-You heard what I said.
لكن يا سيدي. سمعت ما قلته.
-But, sir...
-You heard what I said.
How will this state remain standing?
كيف ستبقى هذه الدولة قائمة؟
Inform all the tribes
in the region immediately.
إبلاغ جميع القبائل. في المنطقة على الفور.
Inform all the tribes
in the region immediately.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
Where are those templars?
أين هي تلك المعابد؟
Halt!
وقف.
Let us rest a bit here.
دعنا نرتاح قليلا هنا.
Check the surroundings.
تحقق من المناطق المحيطة.
We need to weaken the Seljuks
before the crusade.
نحن بحاجة لإضعاف السلاجقة. قبل الحملة الصليبية.
We need to weaken the Seljuks
before the crusade.
You should put more men
in the Seljuk court, Titus.
يجب عليك وضع المزيد من الرجال. في محكمة السلجوق ، تيتوس.
You should put more men
in the Seljuk court, Titus.
Please be rest assured that
we will possess the whole court.
يرجى أن تطمئن إلى ذلك. سنمتلك المحكمة بأكملها.
Please be rest assured that
we will possess the whole court.
There is a group in the Papacy,
who are reluctant about the crusade.
هناك مجموعة في البابوية ،. الذين يترددون في الحملة الصليبية.
There is a group in the Papacy,
who are reluctant about the crusade.
I am not surprised.
أنا لست مندهش.
We need to make a plan that will mobilize
the whole Europe.
نحن بحاجة إلى وضع خطة من شأنها تعبئة. أوروبا كلها.
We need to make a plan that will mobilize
the whole Europe.
We need to do this.
نحن بحاجة للقيام بذلك.
The Christian world should unite
and act for Jerusalem.
يجب أن يتحد العالم المسيحي. والتصرف من أجل القدس.
The Christian world should unite
and act for Jerusalem.
For this, we need to provoke
the Muslims and make them attack us.
لهذا ، نحن بحاجة إلى إثارة. المسلمون وجعلهم يهاجموننا.
For this, we need to provoke
the Muslims and make them attack us.
I have some very valuable prisoners.
لدي بعض السجناء قيمة للغاية.
We can start with them.
يمكننا أن نبدأ معهم.
Calm down, son.
تهدئة يا بني.
Yigit.
Commoner...
العامي.
...you can go to hell.
يمكنك الذهاب الى الجحيم.
-Take us to our destination quickly.
-So you are very keen to die.
خذنا إلى وجهتنا بسرعة. لذلك أنت حريص جدا للموت.
-Take us to our destination quickly.
-So you are very keen to die.
I pity for your beautiful daughter
and your small Shahzade.
أنا أشفق على ابنتك الجميلة. و Shahzade الصغيرة الخاصة بك.
I pity for your beautiful daughter
and your small Shahzade.
Don’t shed a tear for us.
لا تذرف دموعنا.
If you had accepted to be allies with us,
you were to become the Seljuk sultan...
إذا كنت قد قبلت أن تكون حلفاء معنا ،. كنت لتصبح السلطان السلجوقي.
If you had accepted to be allies with us,
you were to become the Seljuk sultan...
...and everything was going to be fine.
-You offered slavery for the Pope.
وكان كل شيء على ما يرام. لقد عرضتم العبودية على البابا.
...and everything was going to be fine.
-You offered slavery for the Pope.
We offered you peace...
قدمنا لك السلام.
...and a new world order.
ونظام عالمي جديد.
We wanted to live side by side.
أردنا أن نعيش جنبا إلى جنب.
But...
لكن.
...the Muslim blood will always be shed.
دماء المسلمين سوف تسفك دائما.
There is no escape from this.
لا مفر من هذا.
And we will shed your blood with
the Muslim allies we have.
ونحن سوف سفك دمك مع. الحلفاء المسلمين لدينا.
And we will shed your blood with
the Muslim allies we have.
You will not succeed.
لن تنجح.
We will see.
سنرى.
In the mean time...
في هذه الأثناء.
...to all your men I had sent to hell...
لجميع رجالك كنت قد أرسلت إلى الجحيم.
...give them my regards.
أعطهم تحياتي.
-The area is safe, sir.
-Good.
المنطقة آمنة يا سيدي. جيد.
-The area is safe, sir.
-Good.
Water the horses.
سقي الخيول.
These too.
هذه ايضا.
-Come on!
-Yeah!
هيا. بلى.
-Come on!
-Yeah!
Come on!
هيا.
You two, go and sit somewhere else.
أنت اثنان ، اذهب واجلس في مكان آخر.
I brought you water. Take it.
أحضرت لك الماء خذها.
Take it.
خذها.
Come on.
هيا.
They are not aware.
انهم ليسوا على علم.
Key! Take the key.
المفتاح خذ المفتاح.
Come on, my girl.
تعال يا فتاتي.
We are in luck.
نحن في الحظ.
The prisoners are running away!
السجناء يفرون.
-Quick, run!
-Get them!
الجري بأستعجال. احضرهم.
-Quick, run!
-Get them!
-Father!
الآب. الآب.
-Are you alright?
-Father!
هل انت بخير؟. الآب.
-Are you alright?
-Father!
Quick, take your brother
and get out of here.
سريع ، خذ أخيك. واخرج من هنا.
Quick, take your brother
and get out of here.
No!
لا.
-Father!
الآب. الآب.
-Quick! Run away!
-No, we cannot leave you in this state.
تشغيل سريع بعيدا. لا ، لا يمكننا تركك في هذه الحالة.
-Quick! Run away!
-No, we cannot leave you in this state.
Take your brother and
get the hell out of here!
خذ أخيك و. اخرج من هنا بحق الجحيم.
Take your brother and
get the hell out of here!
Come on, father! Get up! Come on!
هيا ، الأب.
So you tried to run away!
You will pay for this.
لذلك حاولت الهرب. سوف تدفع لهذا.
So you tried to run away!
You will pay for this.
Father!
الآب.
Have some decency! Dear God!
Have some decency!
هل لديك بعض الحشمة عزيزي الله. لديك بعض الحشمة.
Have some decency! Dear God!
Have some decency!
Great God!
الإله العظيم.
-Father!
الآب. الآب.
Father, stay with us, please!
الأب ، ابق معنا ، من فضلك.
Your first victim was a crusader.
ضحيتك الأولى كانت صليبية.
-Stay with us.
-Be strong, father.
ابقى معنا. كن قويا يا أبي.
-Stay with us.
-Be strong, father.
-Quick, bring some oak leaves.
-Okay.
سريع ، وجلب بعض أوراق البلوط. حسنا.
-Quick, bring some oak leaves.
-Okay.
If we are successful, all the borders
in the region will change.
إذا نجحنا ، كل الحدود. في المنطقة سوف تتغير.
If we are successful, all the borders
in the region will change.
We should not refrain from using
our order’s wealth to save Jerusalem.
لا ينبغي لنا الامتناع عن استخدام. ثروة نظامنا لإنقاذ القدس.
We should not refrain from using
our order’s wealth to save Jerusalem.
We are ready to spend the whole treasury.
نحن على استعداد لقضاء الخزينة بأكملها.
For young men, a new Jerusalem campaign
would be the shortest road to riches.
للشباب ، حملة جديدة في القدس. سيكون أقصر طريق إلى الثروات.
For young men, a new Jerusalem campaign
would be the shortest road to riches.
They will be enlisting by the thousands
to be a member of the crusade army.
سيتم تجنيد الآلاف. ليكون عضوا في الجيش الصليبي.
They will be enlisting by the thousands
to be a member of the crusade army.
The Catalans, the Venetians,
the Marseilleans...
الكاتالونية ، والبندقية ،. مارسيليا.
The Catalans, the Venetians,
the Marseilleans...
...they will be pining for this carnival.
سيكونون متلهفين لهذا الكرنفال.
Well...
حسنا.
...what about the spoilt princes of
Europe, how will we trust them?
ماذا عن الأمراء الفاسدين. أوروبا ، كيف نثق بهم؟
...what about the spoilt princes of
Europe, how will we trust them?
When the Muslims start to fight
with each other...
عندما يبدأ المسلمون في القتال. مع بعض.
When the Muslims start to fight
with each other...
...our job will not be difficult, Titus.
مهمتنا لن تكون صعبة يا تيتوس.
What about the Seljuks, sir?
ماذا عن السلاجقة يا سيدي؟
Anatolia.
الأناضول.
They are on the peak of their power
with Sultan Aladdin.
هم في ذروة قوتهم. مع سلطان علاء الدين.
They are on the peak of their power
with Sultan Aladdin.
When we make the Turks and the grandsons
of Saladin Ayyubi fall out on...
عندما نصنع الأتراك والأحفاد. صلاح الدين الأيوبي تسقط.
When we make the Turks and the grandsons
of Saladin Ayyubi fall out on...
...each other we will reach our goal.
بعضنا البعض سوف نصل إلى هدفنا.
Jerusalem will be ours.
القدس ستكون لنا.
Father, please be strong.
الأب ، من فضلك كن قويا.
We have to go immediately.
علينا أن نذهب على الفور.
You can go.
يمكنك الذهاب.
We can look after ourselves.
يمكننا الاعتناء بأنفسنا.
It will get dark soon.
سوف تحصل على الظلام قريبا.
The jackals would have
already smelled the blood.
سوف ابن آوى لها. رائحة بالفعل الدم.
The jackals would have
already smelled the blood.
-We should go.
-Dogan, bring the horses.
علينا الذهاب. دوجان ، أحضر الخيول.
-We should go.
-Dogan, bring the horses.
It is easy to fend off a crusader brigade.
What about this?
من السهل صد لواء صليبي. ماذا عن هذا؟.
It is easy to fend off a crusader brigade.
What about this?
Ertugrul is lost now.
يضيع Ertugrul الآن.
-God always helps those who get lost.
-He is lost real bad now.
الله يساعد دائما أولئك الذين يضيعون. لقد ضاع سيء الآن.
-God always helps those who get lost.
-He is lost real bad now.
Come on.
هيا.
-What can you do alone as a woman?
-I said we won’t go.
ماذا يمكنك أن تفعل لوحدك كامرأة؟ قلت لن نذهب.
-What can you do alone as a woman?
-I said we won’t go.
We owe you a life.
We will pay our debt one day.
نحن مدينون لك بالحياة. سندفع ديوننا يوم واحد.
We owe you a life.
We will pay our debt one day.
Tell us your name.
أخبرنا باسمك
Ertugrul from Kayi tribe.
Ertugrul من قبيلة كاي.
As you wish.
كما تتمنا.
May God be with you. I wish you good luck.
الله يكون معكم اتمنى لك التوفيق
We should go with them.
يجب أن نذهب معهم.
Is your tribe far?
هل قبيلتك بعيدة؟
Even our money for bad days is finished,
Brother Afsin.
حتى أموالنا للأيام السيئة قد انتهت. الأخ أفسين.
Even our money for bad days is finished,
Brother Afsin.
We can set shop here. If we see that
they are not interested, we can go on.
يمكننا وضع متجر هنا إذا رأينا ذلك. إنهم غير مهتمين ، يمكننا المضي قدمًا.
We can set shop here. If we see that
they are not interested, we can go on.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you. Welcome.
السلام عليكم. والسلام عليكم.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you. Welcome.
Welcome, Gazanfar Aga.
أهلا وسهلا بك ، غضنفر آغا.
You bring joy to Kayi tribe.
كنت تجلب الفرح لقبيلة كاي.
Kurdoglu, my brother. You always
look very healthy, thanks to God.
كوردوغلو يا أخي أنت دائمًا. تبدو صحية للغاية ، بفضل الله.
Kurdoglu, my brother. You always
look very healthy, thanks to God.
Would these moorlands keep a man healthy,
for us to be healthy, Gazanfer?
هل تبقي هذه المستنقعات على رجل يتمتع بصحة جيدة؟ لكي نكون بصحة جيدة يا غزانفر؟
Would these moorlands keep a man healthy,
for us to be healthy, Gazanfer?
No, don’t say that. You look very well.
لا ، لا تقل أنك تبدو جيدًا.
Where is your caravan?
أين القافلة الخاصة بك؟
The caravan is near the black rock.
القافلة بالقرب من الصخرة السوداء.
I came to get permission from Suleyman
Shah to set up a stall in the market.
جئت للحصول على إذن من سليمان. شاه لاقامة كشك في السوق.
I came to get permission from Suleyman
Shah to set up a stall in the market.
How is business?
كيف هو العمل؟
We thank God on what he gives.
نشكر الله على ما يعطيه.
I wanted to come to Kayi to supply
whatever they need before the journey.
كنت أرغب في المجيء إلى كاي لتزويده. كل ما يحتاجونه قبل الرحلة.
I wanted to come to Kayi to supply
whatever they need before the journey.
Thank you, Gazanfer. I hope you meet
your expectations, if God permits.
شكراً لك يا غزانفر أتمنى أن تقابل. توقعاتك ، إذا سمح الله.
Thank you, Gazanfer. I hope you meet
your expectations, if God permits.
Thank you.
شكرا لك.
If Suleyman Shah is available,
I would like to meet him.
إذا سليمان شاه متاح ،. أود مقابلته.
If Suleyman Shah is available,
I would like to meet him.
Tell our Bey that Gazanfer Aga is here.
أخبرنا بك أن غزنفر آغا موجود هنا.
-How much is this?
-He is a mute, sir. Let me help you.
كم ثمن هذا؟. إنه كتم الصوت ، سيدي ، دعني أساعدك.
-How much is this?
-He is a mute, sir. Let me help you.
80 coins.
80 قطعة نقدية.
You look familiar to me.
أنت تبدو مألوفة بالنسبة لي.
This is my first time in your tribe, sir.
هذه هي المرة الأولى لي في قبيلتك يا سيدي.
You probably took me for someone else.
ربما أخذتني لشخص آخر.
Peace be upon you, Suleyman Shah.
السلام عليكم ، سليمان شاه.
And peace be upon you, trader. Welcome.
والسلام عليكم يا تاجر أهلا وسهلا.
You bring joy to us. Come and sit.
تجلب لنا السعادة تعال واجلس.
Suleyman Bey, my eyes are so happy that
they had the chance to see you again.
سليمان بك ، عيني سعيدة للغاية. كان لديهم الفرصة لرؤيتك مرة أخرى.
Suleyman Bey, my eyes are so happy that
they had the chance to see you again.
Please accept my presents. I brought them
from Constantinople for you.
أرجو أن تقبل الهدايا التي أحضرتها. من القسطنطينية لك.
Please accept my presents. I brought them
from Constantinople for you.
You did not have to bother.
لم يكن لديك عناء.
-Kurdoglu, give these to those in need.
-As you wish, Bey.
كوردوغلو ، أعط هذه للمحتاجين. كما يحلو لك ، بك.
-Kurdoglu, give these to those in need.
-As you wish, Bey.
Well?
حسنا؟.
Tell us now. What did those eyes see in
other parts of the world?
أخبرنا الآن ماذا ترى تلك العيون في أجزاء أخرى من العالم؟
Tell us now. What did those eyes see in
other parts of the world?
I wish I was deaf and not hear it.
كنت أتمنى لو كنت أصم ولم أسمع ذلك.
I wish I was blind and not see it, Bey.
أتمنى لو كنت أعمى ولا أراها ، بك.
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟.
Sultan Aladdin controlled Konya but...
سلطان علاء الدين يسيطر على قونية.
...he worries that the fugitive Shahzades
may give him trouble.
إنه قلق من أن شاهزاديس الهارب. قد يعطيه مشكلة.
...he worries that the fugitive Shahzades
may give him trouble.
The Latins ransacked Constantinople.
نهب اللاتين القسطنطينية.
All Orthodox people left the city.
غادر جميع الأرثوذكس المدينة.
There is no order, no peace...
لا يوجد نظام ولا سلام.
...and with the famine now,
everyone is desperate.
ومع المجاعة الآن ،. الجميع يائس.
...and with the famine now,
everyone is desperate.
We heard that the leftovers from
the crusaders were getting restless.
سمعنا أن بقايا الطعام من. كان الصليبيون يشعرون بالقلق.
We heard that the leftovers from
the crusaders were getting restless.
It is obvious that they are up to
something once again.
من الواضح أن ما يصل إلى. شيء مرة أخرى.
It is obvious that they are up to
something once again.
Well...
حسنا.
...how are the common people?
كيف هي عامة الناس؟
They will be on the road again
to find something to eat.
سيكونون على الطريق مرة أخرى. للعثور على شيء للأكل.
They will be on the road again
to find something to eat.
The rumor is that the Pope is calling for
a new crusade to the European princes.
الشائعات هي أن البابا ينادي. حملة صليبية جديدة للأمراء الأوروبيين.
The rumor is that the Pope is calling for
a new crusade to the European princes.
And we Muslims fight against each other.
ونحن المسلمين نقاتل ضد بعضنا البعض.
Sowing discord between us,
fueling the disorder as much as possible.
بذر الشقاق بيننا. تأجيج الاضطراب قدر الإمكان.
Sowing discord between us,
fueling the disorder as much as possible.
From Anatolia to Basra,
everywhere is on fire.
من الأناضول إلى البصرة. في كل مكان على النار.
From Anatolia to Basra,
everywhere is on fire.
This fire will hit us as well, Bey.
هذه النار سوف تضربنا أيضا ، بك.
Please don’t say fire, it upsets me, Bey.
من فضلك لا تقول النار ، فإنه يزعجني ، بك.
I came to seek for permission to sell
my goods in your tribe.
جئت للحصول على إذن للبيع. البضائع الخاصة بي في قبيلتك.
I came to seek for permission to sell
my goods in your tribe.
-You have our permission.
-Thank you.
لديك إذن لدينا. شكرا لك.
-You have our permission.
-Thank you.
Karatoygar has come to the region
to control the Turkmen tribes.
لقد حان Karatoygar إلى المنطقة. للسيطرة على القبائل التركمانية.
Karatoygar has come to the region
to control the Turkmen tribes.
So difficult times await us.
أوقات صعبة للغاية تنتظرنا.
And this girl is from Venetia.
Rosalina, she has noble blood.
وهذه الفتاة من فينيسيا. روزالينا ، لديها دماء نبيلة.
And this girl is from Venetia.
Rosalina, she has noble blood.
A white skin, green eyes.
A rare find, commander.
بشرة بيضاء ، عيون خضراء. اكتشاف نادر ، قائد.
A white skin, green eyes.
A rare find, commander.
And she is very cheap as well.
I am in urgent need of money.
وهي رخيصة جدا أيضا. أنا في حاجة ماسة إلى المال.
And she is very cheap as well.
I am in urgent need of money.
This is a very good opportunity
for you and me.
هذه فرصة جيدة جدا لي ولك.
This is a very good opportunity
for you and me.
What do you say to this, commander?
ماذا تقول لهذا يا قائد؟
They kidnapped her from
the Greek Islands.
خطفوها من. الجزر اليونانية.
They kidnapped her from
the Greek Islands.
She screams beauty and freshness.
إنها تصرخ الجمال والانتعاش.
She is a wild one.
هي واحدة البرية.
I personally trained her.
For a master with good taste.
أنا شخصيا دربتها. للحصول على درجة الماجستير مع الذوق السليم.
I personally trained her.
For a master with good taste.
What about that blond one?
ماذا عن ذلك الاشقر؟
I must say that you have good taste.
يجب أن أقول أن لديك ذوق جيد.
I bought her from the crusader discards.
They brought her in with a ship.
اشتريتها من المرتجع الصليبي. أحضروها مع سفينة.
I bought her from the crusader discards.
They brought her in with a ship.
She is Serbian,
she knows how to treat a man.
هي الصربية ،. هي تعرف كيف تعامل الرجل.
She is Serbian,
she knows how to treat a man.
Enough.
يكفي.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
You don’t need to be afraid of me.
لا تحتاج أن تخاف مني.
I am your master now.
أنا سيدك الآن.
You chose the most expensive one,
commander. But she is worth it.
اخترت أغلى واحد ،. قائد لكنها تستحق ذلك.
You chose the most expensive one,
commander. But she is worth it.
-Sir?
-What happened?
سيدي المحترم؟. ماذا حدث؟.
-Sir?
-What happened?
The crusaders. They were ambushed.
الصليبيون كانوا في كمين.
Didn’t you save them?
لم تنقذهم؟
We were too late.
لقد فات الأوان.
So you were late.
لذلك كنت متأخرا.
-Welcome.
أهلا بك. أهلا بك.
-Come on, help them.
-Help them.
تعال ، ساعدهم. ساعدهم.
-Come on, help them.
-Help them.
Akcakoca, we have a wounded man.
أكاكوكا ، لدينا رجل مصاب.
-Come on.
-Bamsi, take him in.
هيا. بامسي ، خذه في.
-Come on.
-Bamsi, take him in.
-What happened?
-Nothing to worry about.
ماذا حدث؟. لا شيء يدعو للقلق.
-What happened?
-Nothing to worry about.
-You are alright, yes?
-We all are, thank God.
أنت بخير ، نعم؟ كلنا الحمد لله.
-You are alright, yes?
-We all are, thank God.
Ertugrul...
...what happened, my brother?
ماذا حدث يا أخي؟
They were attacked, brother.
I will tell you later.
تعرضوا للهجوم يا أخي. سأخبرك لاحقا.
They were attacked, brother.
I will tell you later.
-Look after them, Ramazan.
-As you wish, Bey.
اعتن بهم يا رمضان. كما يحلو لك ، بك.
-Look after them, Ramazan.
-As you wish, Bey.
Who are they, Gundogdu?
من هم ، جوندوجو؟
I don’t know. He will tell us later.
We will find out soon.
لا أعلم أنه سيخبرنا لاحقًا. سنجد قريبا.
I don’t know. He will tell us later.
We will find out soon.
Sister, what is happening? Who are they?
أخت ، ماذا يحدث؟ من هؤلاء؟.
We will find out soon. We will see.
سنكتشف قريبا سنرى.
The sword hit him right below the rib.
Fortunately the oak leaves stopped...
ضربه السيف مباشرة أسفل الضلع. لحسن الحظ توقف أوراق البلوط.
The sword hit him right below the rib.
Fortunately the oak leaves stopped...
...the bleeding,
otherwise we would have lost him.
النزيف،. وإلا كنا قد فقدناه.
...the bleeding,
otherwise we would have lost him.
-Midwife, bring hot water.
-At once, Akcakoca.
قابلة ، أحضر الماء الساخن. في وقت واحد ، أكاكوكا.
-Midwife, bring hot water.
-At once, Akcakoca.
The leg is bad as well.
But we should fix this wound first.
الساق سيئة كذلك. ولكن يجب أن نصلح هذا الجرح أولاً.
The leg is bad as well.
But we should fix this wound first.
Akcakoca can take it from here.
Let us wait at the side.
Akcakoca يمكن أن تأخذه من هنا. دعونا ننتظر في الجانب.
Akcakoca can take it from here.
Let us wait at the side.
-We cannot leave our father alone, sister.
-Don’t worry.
لا يمكننا ترك والدنا وحده ، أخته. لا تقلق
-We cannot leave our father alone, sister.
-Don’t worry.
Your father is in good hands.
والدك في أيد أمينة.
Thank you very much. You are God sent.
شكرا جزيلا لك يا الله أرسل.
-We brought trouble to you.
-Don’t say that.
جئنا المتاعب لك. لا تقل ذلك.
-We brought trouble to you.
-Don’t say that.
You had more breaths to take,
more bites to eat.
كان لديك المزيد من الأنفاس ، المزيد من لدغات لتناول الطعام.
You had more breaths to take,
more bites to eat.
Where were the crusaders taking you?
أين أخذك الصليبيون؟
I don’t know. They didn’t say.
أنا لا أعرف أنهم لم يقولوا.
I guess they were going to sell us in
the slave market. My father is a trader.
أعتقد أنهم كانوا سيبيعوننا. سوق الرقيق والدي تاجر.
I guess they were going to sell us in
the slave market. My father is a trader.
We were captured in the Mediterranean.
تم القبض علينا في البحر الأبيض المتوسط.
Your father must be a good trader.
Having so many crusaders taking you.
يجب أن يكون والدك تاجر جيد. وجود الكثير من الصليبيين يأخذك.
Your father must be a good trader.
Having so many crusaders taking you.
Yes.
نعم فعلا.
We were rich.
كنا أغنياء.
But we don’t have anything left now.
ولكن ليس لدينا أي شيء غادر الآن.
Well...
حسنا.
...which tribe is this?
أي قبيلة هذا؟
You are in Kayi tribe.
أنت في قبيلة كاي.
I am the son of
the tribe Bey, Suleyman Shah.
أنا ابن. قبيلة بك ، سليمان شاه.
I am the son of
the tribe Bey, Suleyman Shah.
We owe you three lives.
نحن مدينون لك بثلاثة أرواح.
-Do you want to be freed from slavery?
-Yes.
هل تريد أن تتحرر من العبودية؟ نعم فعلا.
-Do you want to be freed from slavery?
-Yes.
-Then, kill this man.
-No!
ثم ، اقتل هذا الرجل. لا.
-Then, kill this man.
-No!
I will buy and then free you.
سأشتري ثم أفرغك.
Commander, you are furious.
First calm down...
قائد ، أنت غاضب. أول تهدئة.
Commander, you are furious.
First calm down...
Shut your mouth.
اصمت.
Don’t let me kill you as well.
لا تدعني أقتلك كذلك.
Sir, please spare me for my children.
سيدي ، يرجى تجنيبي لأطفالي.
You are good for nothing.
أنت جيد من أجل لا شيء.
Do it!
افعلها.
-I can’t.
-I said do it!
لا استطيع قلت افعلها.
-I can’t.
-I said do it!
I’m freeing you!
أنا تحرير لك.
A slave that can kill someone
to be free...
عبدا يمكنه قتل شخص ما. لتكون حرا.
A slave that can kill someone
to be free...
...can kill her master one day as well.
يمكن أن تقتل سيدها يوم واحد كذلك.
Get ready, we are going!
الاستعداد ، نحن ذاهبون.
Translation: Suzan Mıhladız